Then Adler session, we analyzed the start of any process.
There were three main things in start up in process.
One of them was to create beside the process.
Right.
So what exactly is Sago process and what does it do?
In this session, we will cover Sago and its start up process.
We'll also walk through the code and see how Sago stacks up the system so well and also how it starts
a new process when activity management service requests to do so.
In a previous lecture, we discussed about the healing process, and we have seen how it starts the
zygote process.
We also walk product code, right?
So in this session we will start right from there and continue with the EGOT process.
We'll see how zygote starts the systems of up and wait for the request from activity management service
or aims to create a new process.
In Android, the Android runtime or the Dalvik virtual machine, the application process and the system
server process that runs the key pieces of system are all created by the zygote process.
It leads the application process and the system server a process using both mechanism.
So both mechanism means nothing but creates a new process by duplicating the existing process from which
it is called.
So since zygote process will create a virtual mission or Android runtime when it starts, the application
process and the system process created by this format can sum and automatically update a copy of the
Android runtime instance internally.
So let's look at the code and see how zygote starts up and how it calls the start system sidebar and
then how it waits for payments or activity management services.
So you need dirt.
Good 64 Odyssey.
So we had looked at this pilot in our previous session.
So this file is basically a configuration for zygote process.
As I said earlier in, it is a very simple language and there are some commands, some import statements.
So here you can see in this file it says to create a service named zygote with this process.
So this is the this is basically the program which it has to execute.
And then later, we are passing some parameters.
So here we have the start system, sort of a parameter, then zygote parameter then.
So we are sending some path.
The second line that is a statement classmate.
So this is that the name of this particular program or zygote is mean.
So the zygote or this service is referenced in the RC files with the name Mean.
Okay.
So in any programming language, there is one file called any dot RC, which is a kind of main function.
So here you can find that.
So this a big file.
So this is very similar to our main function within Java or C++ or C language.
You have we have this main function, right?
We get the go and start.
So this is very similar to that.
So in a dot, RC is the main file or main function which gets insignificant signature.
And this will do all the import and all the operations and it will also call these RC files internally.
So if you come down, you can see here that last start main.
So this is basically a command to start a class named as Main.
So this will basically start the cycle.
Okay.
So this will trigger the statement, will basically start this configuration or this process.
So now this process will start at process 64, right?
So that our process 64 basically points to I mean, don't sleep.
So don't start executing from this main function.
Okay.
As you can see, the main function basically does a lot of initialization and it will also loop through
the argument which is passed in from here.
So these arguments basically loop through those arguments and it will set many variables.
So here you can see the START system server is initialize defaults first and then it checks.
If it has a parameter, then it sets its true.
True.
So this basically says to start the systems over or not and then it takes if it is true, then add this
argument and at the bottom if it is zygote, then start the runtime with this package name and pass
this argument.
So this is basically passing these arguments to this Java package.
So this is a Java package.
You can see this package name, right?
It seems to be a dollar package.
And it's it's a giant package.
We'll look at it soon.
So and it's basically parsing all these parameters.
And then what exactly is runtime?
So runtime then object all app runtime.
You can see the app runtime inherits from Android runtime.
Okay.
It's basically running the start function within android runtime.
This start function should be from android runtime.
Let's go to android runtime.
Yeah.
You can see the start function.
Right.
So this is the one which is going to get called to the.
So first one class name is nothing but.
The zygote in.
Plus.
Okay, this is the one.
So in the start process of Android runtime, you can see it takes in all these parameters.
It is passed from app mean and it does a lot of initialization here.
And when we come down we can see start VM.
So it starts the virtual machine.
So this basically starts the Java virtual machine and start, right?
This function is basically to register the DNI for the Android runtime or the dynamic virtual machine.
So this is basically registers the Android functions and this starts the virtual machine.
And then if you come down, you can see here it's trying to find the main function, but it's trying
to call the main function.
So this will eventually say good in it.
Plus.
Yeah.
So then the control goes to zygote in it, this one.
So from here it goes to the Java layer.
So this communication happens through tonight and once we are inside, good in it.
So let's start from the main.
So here, so the arguments are being passed.
So this is the same argument which comes from here and then you come down and see it does similar things,
like it goes to the arguments and it picks up the START system server and it configures the stock system.
So to to if you come further down here, you can see it's starting the system server by forking.
So here, if this value is true, it's true because we have passed that.
So then it's true and it supports the system.
So yeah.
So this is the point where we start the system.
So what?
And further, if you come down, we can see that it runs a select loop and if we go inside this.
So this is within good server, not Java.
So here we can see that.
Is it infinite loop?
So this loop will be always running and it basically waiting for some client request.
So this will basically wait for the activity manager service to like just to create a new child process.
So this infinite loop is basically responsible whenever a new application has to be started.
Activity Management Service will basically request.
The request will basically come here and it will start the process.
Okay.
So now we have seen how the system sort of starts up so from here and then finally how it gets into
a loop, an infinite loop and waits for a request.
So to summarize, the zygote process does the following steps.
So it creates an app runtime from here and calls the start method to start the zygote process.
And from here it creates the Dalvik virtual machine.
And it disturbs the DNA for the DBM and then it goes the zygote init process.
So from here the control goes through the Java world.
So the control comes to java init.
Yeah.
And this process is through DNA.
And then here does the same thing.
It goes through the arguments and initializes some of the variables.
And finally it talks or starts the system server.
And then here it gets into an infinite loop.
And this will wait for error for the request from Activity Management Service.
So that's all about as I got processed.
I hope you learn something out of this video, and if you like the video, please subscribe so that
I can continue creating videos.
Thank you.